cultofpedagogy.com 2019-06-25

# Privacy Policy | Cult of Pedagogy

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://www.cultofpedagogy.com.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on this site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Contact forms

If you submit a contact form on the Contact page of this site, you must enter a name, email address, and a message. Once that form is submitted, the email address is kept in our email system, where we only use it to respond to your inquiry. The email address is kept in our email archives as a record of our communication, but we can remove it if you request that from us. You can do this by simply replying to the email we send or by submitting another contact form asking us to remove your email from our system.

Names and email addresses submitted through contact forms are never used for marketing purposes, and they they are never shared with anyone outside of Cult of Pedagogy.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you are required to leave your name and email address. For your convenience, we save this information in cookies so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. Your email address will not be visible to other readers. If you would like your email address removed, please contact us using our [contact form](https://www.cultofpedagogy.com/contact/) and we can manually remove the email address from our system.

### Email subscriptions

When you subscribe to our email list, we collect your email address so we can send you emails. You may opt out of this list at any time by sending us a request via email, through our [contact form](https://www.cultofpedagogy.com/contact/), or by simply clicking the unsubscribe link that appears at the bottom of every email we send.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

  * We use a tool called Google Analytics to collect information about use of this site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve this site. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html) (as amended for government websites) and the [Google Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html). You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by [disabling cookies](https://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml) on your browser.
  * Information about your visit to Cult of Pedagogy is collected through the [Facebok Pixel](https://www.facebook.com/business/help/742478679120153), which is equivalent to a cookie. This allows Facebook to help us  customize the advertisements we might want to show you on Facebook. When we want to place an advertisement on Facebook for a particular product, the Pixel can help us determine which visitors to our site might be interested in that product based on the pages they visited here.​

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on the Forums of our website, we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us, through our [contact form](https://www.cultofpedagogy.com/contact/). You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## How Your Data is Shared With Other Sites

Cult of Pedagogy is a participant in several affiliate programs, which allows us to earn a referral fee for sales made on other sites through our referral links. When you visit those sites through our links, those other sites establish a cookie that will remember which site referred you for a set period of time. If you make a purchase during that time, Cult of Pedagogy will receive a referral fee. As of May 2018, the affiliate programs we participate in are as follows: Amazon Associates Program, the 40 Hour Teacher Workweek Club, and Blend Education.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.

This policy was last modified on May 19, 2018.

* * *
